Hello! From this video, you will learn how it
was possible to add infinite funds to your Steam
account by exploiting a flaw in the integration
with the payment service. The vulnerability was
reported on Hackerone by 'drbrix' who got $7,500
for it. The link to the original report is in the
description. I also created hands-on labs
where you can reproduce the vulnerability.
Watch the video until the end to see how you can
access them. I will also have a gift for you. But
for now, enjoy the video! For those of you who
don't know, Steam is a place where you buy games.
The hunter wanted to find a bug in the
functionality of adding funds. Let's
see how the flow looked normally. First, in
Steam, you choose the amount you want to add,
fill in your address, choose the payment method
and information like this. The process consists
of multiple requests but for us the last two ones
are the most important. POST to inittransaction
with all this data as parameters. In response
to that, there is a JSON which contains
transaction_id. What probably happens on the
backend, Steam adds this transaction to the
database with the transaction_id, amount of funds
to add, the user and other data about it. Next,
there's a GET request to externallink endpoint
with transaction_id as the parameter. In the
HTML of the response, there is a form
that will be sent to Smart2Pay server.
I chose Przelewy24 as my payment provider. But
that's a local polish company. For a global firm
like Steam, it could be hard to integrate with
different providers for different countries.
That's why they use Smart2Pay. It's a bridge
between Steam and payment methods in the whole
world. Steam integrates with one Smart2Pay API
which on the other side integrates with over
200 payment methods for different countries. So
Steam must somehow redirect me to Smart2Pay with
proper parameters. Namely, there must be an amount
which I am supposed to pay and the transaction_id.
But I'm a hacker. You can't just tell me to not
modify those parameters. What you can do, however,
is sign them with a secret I don't
know using a hash. Hash is a one-way
function that takes some input and
generates a hash which looks like this.
For SHA256 it has 64 characters when
written in hex format. It was generated
based on the parameters I created in Steam
and a secret value that I don't know.
By seeing the hash, I can't guess the values used
to generate it. And if I only change one character
in any of those parameters, the hash would
look completely different. How does this help?
The secret is shared between Steam and Smart2Pay.
When I send the POST request to Smart2Pay,
it also creates a hash based on my values and
the secret. It then compares the hash that I
send with what Smart2Pay things it should be. If
I would change the amount or any other parameter,
the hash would no longer be valid and the
transaction would be rejected. If it's valid,
Smart2Pay communicates with the chosen payment
provider and the transaction is finalised.
In case of this bug, we don't really care about
integrations between Smart2Pay and payment
providers but rather between Steam and Smart2Pay.
And after the transaction is completed, no data is
sent to Steam on the client-side. What happens on
the backend is that Smart2Pay sends an information
to Steam that the transaction with specific
id was completed. It can be done for example
using a webhook. Then, Steam looks into its
database for this transaction, adds funds to the
proper user and marks the transaction as complete.
So where's the bug? Let's take a closer look at
how exactly do these systems create a string
from parameters when calculating a signature.
Turns out that they were using the parameters
one next to another, without any separators.
So for my body, the string would look like
this. SHA256 hash is calculated using this value
and a secret at the end. So this is the request
that sent to Smart2Pay API. Then, Smart2Pay takes
the whole request body and splits it first by
& and then by =. And those characters are not
in the string used for calculation. Considering
this, all these requests would be equivalent.
What can you do with that? You can arbitrarily put
& and = in the body. However, you still can't add
or modify any values. But if your email
happened to contain a parameter name and value,
you could overwrite the existing parameters
that were used when generating a signature.
So you can create a Steam account with
email gregAmount100greg@example.com.
Then, you can create a new transaction
in Steam for as high value as you can.
In Poland, it's 400 PLN so the amount parameter
will be 40 000. Then, Steam creates a new
transaction in the database with amount 40 000 and
generates a valid signature for your parameters.
Next, before sending the request to Smart2Pay,
you modify the body.
You move the = from the original amount parameter.
Instead of
Amount=40000 you want to have Amount4=0000.
Because Amount4 is a parameter that
will never be used by Smart2Pay API.
Then, you add & and = inside your email to
add the new Amount parameter with the value100.
You didn't modify anything besides
& and = so the signature is still valid
But Smart2Pay sees the Amount parameter
with value 100. So you proceed to pay 1 PLN.
After the transaction is complete, Smart2Pay
sends a webhook to Steam that the transaction
with ID from step 3 is complete. Then, Steam takes
a look into the database, finds a transaction with
this ID and sees that it has an amount of 400 PLN
so it adds 400 PLN to your account when you only
paid 1 PLN. The vulnerability was classified
as critical and hunter was awarded $7,500.
Thank you for watching the video until the
end. You can access hands-on labs if you are
a subscriber of BBRE Premium. Apart from that,
you will also receive even better version of
my newsletter with the best hacking tips and
tricks, tool tutorials and many many more. And
to show how much I appreciate you for watching
the whole video, here is a code for 25% off:
AMOUNT100. With that, you can get BBRE Premium
for only $5 a month. You can only use the code
until 9th September but it will be valid forever
which means you will get 25% off every single
recurrence of the subscription. Find more
details at premium.bugbountyxplained.com
For now, thank you for watching and goodbye!
Ifthey use secrets that are as complex as these examples from the documentation,
thenyou could easily break those hashes...